# CRISTIAN ARIZA

## FULL STACK DEVELOPER

+54 9 11 2388-5841 | mecrisariza@gmail.com | crisariza.com | linkedin.com/in/crisariza | Buenos Aires, Argentina (UTC -3)

## **EDUCATION**

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

HENRY BOOTCAMP | REMOTE | DEC 2020-FEB 2021

- Acquired advanced proficiency in full-stack development encompassing both front-end and back-end domains during an intensive bootcamp.
- Achieved comprehensive expertise in proficient problem-solving.

## **SKILLS**

#### **FRONT END**

React, Redux, Next, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, TailwindCSS, API REST, JSON WebToken

#### **BACK END**

Python, Git, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Sequelize

## **LANGUAGES**

English | Fluent (C2) Spanish | Fluent (C2)

## **SUMMARY**

Developer with 2 years of experience. Looking forward to creating new complex software engineering projects. Thrilled to use programming skills to help an amazing company create a fantastic product. Excited about business, startups, crypto and cutting-edge tech. Dedicated to creating code quality over quantity.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER - FRONT END DEVELOPER

ACCENTURE | BUENOS AIRES (REMOTE) | MAY 2021 - PRESENT

- Developed a platform that managed +150 web applications, providing security solutions with a modern and simple to use experience.
- Saved +20 hours per month by innovating in a new automated content delivery to developers, using a modern framework such as NextJS.
- Created a front-end from scratch using React, Redux and TailwindCSS, providing a phenomenal user experience and interface.
- Improved the API queries speed by 30% through requiring and sending only the needed JSON data, which enhanced the overall app experience.
- Increased satisfaction rate versus the old platform from 80% to 95% by implementing feedback provided from developers, also improving the overall communication.
- Promoted within 12 months for outstanding performance from Junior to Semi-Senior role, acquiring more responsibilities, advanced tasks and making critical thinking.

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

HENRY | REMOTE | MAR 2021 - APR 2021

- Led a 5+ person team in developing an ecommerce website with secure authentication, automated emails, payment integration, and search functionality.
- Implemented user-friendly features like a product cart and streamlined paywall experience.
- Increased the back-end response time by 50% through better queries in PostgreSQL with Sequelize, accomplishing a better user experience.
- Decreased loading times by 40% in the front-end using techniques such as lazy-loading, reducing server calls, reducing image sizes, and more.
- Decreased the loading times of the website by 20% through optimizing the React components states using Redux, leading to a more modular code.
- Designed the user interface and experience with modern, simple and beautiful styles.